<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Using the analyzer on Yauaa - Yet Another UserAgent Analyzer</title><link>/using/</link><description>Recent content in Using the analyzer on Yauaa - Yet Another UserAgent Analyzer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/using/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>User-Agent Client Hints</title><link>/using/clienthints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/using/clienthints/</guid><description>The User-Agent and the User-Agent Client Hints From about 2019 onward several of the main browsers (Firefox/Chromium/Chrome/Edge/&amp;hellip;) have been making steps to reduce the information in the User-Agent. The main reason is that the User-Agents so far have so much detailled information that it became so unique that some could be used as a device id for tracking purposes.
In addition, steps are taken to provide information to website builders that is intended to be sufficient for running a website and less prone to tracking people.</description></item><item><title>Memory usage</title><link>/using/memoryusage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/using/memoryusage/</guid><description>The system relies heavily on HashMaps to quickly find the rules that need to be fired.
Some fields only require a handful of rules where others have a lot of them. This means that it depends on the fields that have been requested how many rules are kept in the system and thus how much memory is used to store the rules in. To get an idea of the relative memory impact of the rules needed for a specific field.</description></item><item><title>The demonstration webservlet</title><link>/using/webservlet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/using/webservlet/</guid><description>Part of the distribution is a war file that is a servlet that has a webinterface and some APIs that allow you to try things out.
This servlet can be downloaded via
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;nl.basjes.parse.useragent&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;yauaa-webapp&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;7.0.0&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;type&amp;gt;war&amp;lt;/type&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; NOTE that this is a DEMONSTRATION servlet!
It is simply the library in a servlet, no optimizations or smart memory settings have been done at all.
Docker Starting with version 5.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes</title><link>/using/kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/using/kubernetes/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with Kubernetes and the code below &amp;ldquo;works on my cluster&amp;rdquo;.
Basic Service First create a dedicated namespace and a very basic deployment to run this image 3 times and exposes it as a Service that simply does http.
apiVersion: v1 kind: Namespace metadata: name: yauaa --- apiVersion: apps/v1 kind: Deployment metadata: name: yauaa namespace: yauaa spec: selector: matchLabels: app: yauaa replicas: 3 template: metadata: labels: app: yauaa spec: containers: - name: yauaa image: nielsbasjes/yauaa:7.</description></item><item><title>Licence</title><link>/using/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/using/license/</guid><description>Apache License Version 2.0, January 2004 https://www.apache.org/licenses/
TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR USE, REPRODUCTION, AND DISTRIBUTION Definitions. License shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
Licensor shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.
Legal Entity shall mean the union of the acting entity and all other entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with that entity.</description></item></channel></rss>